http://www.knowledgematters.com/about/privacy/

OUR COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY
We value your privacy.
We provide this statement to describe our information practices and the way your information is collected and used. By accessing or using our website(s), content and products, you are agreeing with the policy terms of this Privacy Statement.
If at any time you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement, please contact as provided below.
THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW IT IS USED
1) Website(s):
The following applies to all information collected or submitted on KMI’s operated website(s). On some pages, you can order products, make requests, submit information, and register to receive materials. The types of personal information collected at these pages may include; name, address, email address, phone number, credit/debit card information, as well as other similar personal information.
On some pages, you can submit information about other people. For example, if you register a student sub-user, you may need to submit the student’s email and/or mailing address. In these circumstances, the types of personal information collected may be:
name, address, phone number, and/or email address. While student first name, last name combinations are readily available to the public, we nevertheless provide a method for preventing students from entering more than a single initial for last name. If you would like this feature turned on for your district, contact support@knowledgematters.com. Email addresses often follow a standard format and are readily guessable by the public. However, for schools that don’t want to expose student emails, we offer an option to use unique, computer generated usernames instead of email addresses. For more info on using this option, click here.
We also collect and store the results of each sub-users progress through the course materials which will be available to the holder of the license of the services for purposes of assessment. We do not store any official grades. We store only assignment-level grade recommendations for student simulation and quiz work. All recommendations are subject to correction, adjustment, curving, etc. by the instructor before becoming final assignment grades. We do not store any official assignment grades, mid-term grades, final grades, or transcript-level data. Knowledge Matters does NOT authorize any district to use KMI systems as a repository for official district assignment, midterm, final or transcript-level grades at any time. To lessen the total amount of student assignment work and grade recommendations on our systems, beginning July 2018, we will permanently delete any student work and grade recommendation data for courses ending more than 12 months prior. Instructors should export any data needed prior to that time. For information on how to do this, click here.
Data is retained only for educational purposes. With the submission of a written request, a student’s parent/legal guardian may request the deletion of the student’s data.
We store personally identifiable information in a secure manner, and also use Secure Sockets Layer encrypted connections to transmit your payment-related personally identifiable information to further protect its privacy. We may also collect unique usage information, which does NOT include personally identifiable information, to assist us in understanding our customers’ use patterns and for use in developing new educational products and services.
2) Content Products
Our content products do NOT collect personally identifiable information.
Content Products can be uninstalled from your computer at any time by using the standard Add or Remove Programs feature in the Windows Control Panel.
3) Monitoring/Collection of Information
To assist us in supporting the Services and for future product development, we monitor and collect anonymous usage statistics.
The information gathered is used to accurately track the number of people using our products and other non-personal information.
4) Use of Information
a) We will not share your personally identifiable information with third parties without your consent (subject to the limited exceptions identified below) and at the time you are asked for this information or for consent, we will inform you of:
The personally identifiable information to be shared
The identity of the third party
A link to the third party's privacy statement, if available
Please understand that we may share your information with third parties under the following limited circumstances:
If we use third party contractors to provide services to us or on our behalf. We do require such contractors to maintain personally identifiable information as confidential, and to only use it on our behalf.
If we, in good faith, are required to disclose it to comply with legal processes, or we need to do so to protect your, our or the public's rights or property interests.
If our company is involved in a sale, merger, or any other combination with a third party. In such circumstances, the surviving entity will be responsible for this Privacy Policy and the personally identifiable information collected from you.
b) To permit your efficient use of our websites, products and services, we use cookies (small files stored in your computer), for the purpose of maintaining your login status. Please note that cookies are not used to access your payment information. This information can only be accessed when you enter your name and password.
c) Periodically, we may aggregate data at the class, school, state or national level to allow teachers to compare class performance against state and national averages. All such data will be aggregated and no personally identifiable information will be disclosed.
d) Periodically, we may send e-mails to users of our products and services who have indicated an interest in receiving news, updates, special offers and other information relating to our products and services, and to select third party products and services. You may elect to unsubscribe to these communications by accessing your account information through the My Account section of the KMI website, or by clicking on the link provided at the bottom of our e-mails to you.
e) If you choose not to submit personal information, or if you choose to configure your browser to remove or reject cookies or other passive data collection, you will not be able to fully utilize our products, services and website features.
f) Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13.
The license holder is responsible for assuring that each student granted access to the services is over the age of 13. Anyone identified as being under age 13 will be restricted from accessing or using any of our products or services that require them to enter additional personally identifiable information, and they will not be permitted to purchase any of our products or services. They may access portions of our websites without additional personally identifiable information being collected.
g) We may periodically update our Privacy Policy. Please understand that it is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy frequently to remain informed about any changes to it. Your continued use of our website or content products will indicate your acceptance of any changes we do make. Our most current Privacy Policy will always be available for your review on http://www.KnowledgeMatters.com. We will provide prominent notice before making material changes to our privacy policy for school services.
h) How to Contact Us
While we strive for error free performance, we cannot always catch an unintended privacy issue. As a result, we encourage your questions and comments about any privacy concerns, about this Privacy Policy, or about any of our products and services. Please direct them to us by sending an email to info@KnowledgeMatters.com.
Last Modified: September 28, 2018
PRODUCTS
High School
College
Pro
SIGN IN
Sign in to Virtual Business
Sign in to ProSim
©2020 Knowledge Matters, Inc. All rights reserved.
